The very same company that just got
hacked by a rogue open AAI model just
got acquired for $13 billion by none
other than Nvidia. Jensen Huang believes
so strongly in owning open-source models
in America and he's made his biggest
purchase yet. But that's not without
cause. Nvidia just reported their
earnings and they had a record quarter.
They earned almost hundred billion in
just 3 months and the company is growing
100% year-over-year. This is
unprecedented for the most valuable
company in the world worth over $5
trillion. And every single bank has
raised their price targets for the
Nvidia stock. But that's not all. In
this week's roundup, we had a new secret
model that revealed to be GPU's new GLM
5.3 Flash, which competes at the level
of Fable and OpenAI GPT 5.6, but at a
fraction of the cost. We've got Leopold
updates, unfortunately, of the bad kind
where he is being probed by the SEC
where they've subpoenaed a bunch of
banks for accusations of insider
trading. And we finally have an update
on robots from the worlds of Whimo,
autonomous driving, and Tesla. All that
and more on this week's roundup. To
start with the Nvidia quarterly revenue,
I want to give you a sense of how
outrageous this company is. Nvidia's
quarterly revenue now exceeds the annual
revenue of roughly $480 of the S&P 500.
That is a crazy statistic how big it is.
Nvidia is printing about just over a
billion dollars in cash every single day
that it operates. So the day you're
listening to this, Nvidia is printing a
billion dollars of revenue. And that
number is going to go up. They're
projecting huge amounts of growth over
the next quarter. And they're guiding
now for 70% year-over-year growth in
2028 relative to the expectations which
were 44%. So this earnings report was
about as good as you can guess. And Wall
Street's kind of rewarding them now. I
mean, the stock is up. It was down after
trading, but it is now up 7% early
market. We're looking on screen now at
all the banks that have changed their
price target after reading this earnings
report. pretty much every single one of
them has raised it significantly higher
with the highest being $420 per share
and four like to grow that much as a $5
trillion company is a meaningful amount
of revenue and I think this is very high
signal that the market's still in a
really strong spot. Nvidia is basically
saying like hey guys we know we have a
lot of competition. We know everyone's
trying to build their own thing. In fact
Jensen was on CNBC yesterday and he was
asked about OpenAI's jalapeno chip. I
don't know if you saw the CJs. It was
very cool. Um because Jalapeno is a
really great model and they are a really
great chip and they came out and said,
"Hey, this is actually more efficient
than the Nvidia chips." And Jensen was
like, "Dude, we're we're the kings here.
We've been doing this for 33 years.
You've been doing this for 3 months. Uh
we'll we'll talk to you when you've
actually produced a chip when you've put
it into data centers and when you've
scaled this thing." Um he does not seem
concerned. The market really liked that.
And now it seems like I mean Nvidia is
really off the races and there's no end
in sight. They everyone wants the chips.
They are sold out for as much as they
can make them. They're basically
operating fully at capacity and they
have a very clear path to dominating
more and more of the industry. They're
growing bigger by the day. They now are
working with five of the largest banks
in the world to help fund the buildout
of more data centers using Nvidia GPUs.
And it's just like unbelievable
business. The entire world of AI is
centered around this one company. And
the earnest report is saying it's going
to be like this for a while. So buckle
up because we are up only for the
foreseeable future. I I just want to
show everyone a chart which basically
shows uh Nvidia's revenue breakdown over
the last um you know a year or so and
it's just absolutely exponential and
crazy. Now I I want to give a bit of
background as to why this is happening
with Nvidia especially recently like why
do they continue to earn more money even
though everyone's accusing them of you
know building up this massive bubble.
Well there's a few things that are
happening. The most obvious one being is
they've just raised the prices of all
their GPUs by 15%. Now granted, a lot of
that is because the cost of memory has
absolutely soared. So, you know, those
memory stocks have also been very
volatile recently. Nvidia has to pay the
most for memory to build their own GPU.
So, that's a main reason why they're
projecting more revenue in the future.
That may not necessarily correlate with
the profit side of things. The second
thing is, you know, your point around
Jalapeno, which is OpenAI's new uh
custom AI chip, which they're building
themselves. Typically, they buy from
Nvidia, but now they're building their
own selves. people, some people see this
as a potential threat, you know, like
Google's TPUs are to to Nvidia's kind of
moat. And Jensen's response is simply,
we own the moat for generalized GPUs,
for generalized AI chips. That means any
AI lab, whether you are a Neolab, so a
smaller AI lab or a large hyperscaler,
or whether you are anthropic or open
AAI, can use Nvidia GPUs for whatever
type of model. And by the way, it's not
just LLBs. It's financial models. It's
fine-tuned models. It's models that can
help make scientific breakthroughs.
Jensen owns that entire mode. When you
compare it to what Open Air has built,
Jalapeno, that's known as an ASIC. It's
a very specialized thing. They have to
prove that out at scale. We haven't even
seen these things in operations. We're
going to see it by the end of the year.
So, Nvidia's response to this is we
still very much control 70 to 85% of the
entire market and we aren't going
anywhere. Now, the second bit of news on
Nvidia that I'm most excited about is
this acquisition, Josh, the $13 billion
acquisition of this open-source platform
called Hugging Face. Now, for those of
you who don't know, HuggingFace is
basically this platform which hosts
opensource AI models. So, typically when
you are an AI lab and you can be any AI
lab, if you launch an open model, you
can deposit it or upload it onto the
hugging face platform. It's where
everyone goes to check out the latest
open source model and you can do a few
things when you're on this platform. You
can upload your own data sets to
fine-tune different open models to kind
of create your own version. A very good
example I like to use is uh for Jeepu.
You know all their GLM models. They have
about I think it's like 10 official
models, but there are collectively
around 155,000 GLM models that exist on
HuggingFace and some are financially
tuned for financial trading. Some are
financially tuned for research and all
these other different niche use cases.
And you can go up sign up on an account
and get access to it. Now, I ask myself,
why on earth is Jensen paying 50x the
amount of money that HuggingFace earns
to acquire this open-source model? Like,
like, doesn't he just care about
anthropic and open AAI? Well, the answer
is simple. Jensen cares deeply about
open source because he believes in a
world where it's not just going to be
Claude or GPT running the world. It'll
be hundreds and hundreds of very niche
and also very broad models that run the
world and people can collaboratively use
different models at different times.
Agents run the entire world. Why this is
a bullc case for Nvidia and Jensen in
particular is guess what they all need
to run on his GPUs. So he's been
investing heavily. He he invested in um
Poolside I believe last week for $9
billion to acquire 100 of their
employees so that he can build new open
models. He's investing tens of billions
of dollars in Neatron which is Nvidia's
own open source model over the next
couple of years. And now he's made the
third and biggest purchase of his entire
kind of like focus for open source. So
this is a very uh specific strategy that
I think the banks are rewarding and
that's why they're raising their price
targets as well.
>> It's amazing to see all these
acquisitions happening. We have open
router now we have hugging face going.
Hugging face is essentially the GitHub
for open source AI. It's where everyone
goes to build these things. It seems
like there's three reasons they would do
this and there's three reasons why
Nvidia has kind of been very adamant
about moving to open source. The first
being what we just discussed. Open AAI
is building their own custom chips.
Google is building their own custom
chips. Amazon's building their own
custom chips. Everyone is trying to
build alternatives to the Nvidia GPUs.
It's very difficult to do, but they're
working on it. So, open source is a
hedge in a way against its own best
customers where it allows them to find
more use cases, more need and demand for
tokens that can be generated in the case
that they lose some of that market share
to these other large companies. The
second is like open weights seems to
very much be where the volume is going.
We're starting to see the trend somewhat
oify in the sense that open weights
models and open source models are
producing a lot more tokens because they
are cheaper to use. They're mostly
effective enough to get the job done for
most people and a lot less tokens are
going towards frontier intelligence to
some extent. That frontier intelligence
is much higher profit margins. It's
going to be worth a tremendous amount of
money for the people that use it. But
the amount of use cases that require
frontier intelligence are going down
because the quality of the open source
models are going up so quickly. So
therefore um why would you not lean into
that? And if you are a GPU provider who
gets paid per token generated and your
performance per watt to generate tokens
and how many tokens you can generate on
like a per second basis, open weights is
definitely where you want to be. You
want to be able to cater towards the
open source community that is going to
be generating a tremendous amount of
this inference. And then the final part
is just like the moat is continuing to
move up the stack. So like we have the
GPUs then Nvidia is going to kind of
optimize these models built for CUDA
which works by default with their GPUs
and they will be a one-click deployment
onto the NVIDIA cloud. And there's just
this huge vertical integration that they
get by being supportive of open source
and building tools for the open source
community to very easily deploy on their
GPUs. And that seems like the strategy
and that is a strategy that is going to
perform very well because as we know the
cloud-based businesses in these
companies have insane profit margins.
They print cash and Nvidia is like right
in the middle of that. So really
exciting news from Nvidia this week.
>> Can I can I put my tinfall hound for a
second?
>> You you reminded me of something just
now. So Nvidia actually doesn't have a
really good cloud business at all which
seems remarkable for the guys that
actually create the GPUs that they then
sell to Amazon and Google. Don't count
them out. they make a bank of money.
Well, do you know about the margins for
these cloud providers? So, like okay,
typically when AWS has their cloud
system like forget about AI, right? And
Google has what is it? Google cloud GCP,
they typically make around 80% margins,
but with AI cloud, they make only 40 to
50% because guess who's taking the bulk
of the of the profit? It's Jensen,
right?
>> And so, they kind of want to be
independent. They want to build their
own ships. But Jensen hasn't been
focused on building his own cloud
provider. uh they had a service called
DGX and it kind of didn't make much
money at all. My conspiracy theory is
this. He's purchasing hugging face which
one of their mainly used products is
this thing called uh the inference
service where basically not only can you
go on and download these open models and
there hundreds of thousand there's
actually actually 3 million of them but
you can inference them there on the
platform by just kind of clicking a
button and that gets routed to different
uh like neoclouds. So my whole thing is
Jensen is not only providing the chips,
but he's buying a company where he can
effectively churn into his own cloud
business that can compete with AWS and
GCP. It's a really genius thing cuz he
just focuses on open source models, but
he can build that out into private
models in the future if he so chooses to
do it. The second thing is remember last
week when we spoke about Nvidia raising
$500 billion to basically back a lot of
the purchases that end up going back to
himself. Well, a question that we had on
that show was what happens if he can't
sell the chips? Well, guess what? If
he's purchased Hugging Face, he could
just sell the chips to Hugging Face to
serve that same cloud business. So,
there is like this kind of circular
virtuous loop, but it makes sense from a
business sense. And I think that that's
how he might be trying to play it. It's
It is a very smart business model. I
like seeing Nvidia expand beyond just
making bleeding edge GPUs. He's like a
very smart businessman, obviously.
>> And Jensen we trust, man. the dude, he's
got to figure it out. He's been
projecting these crazy revenue numbers
for years now, and he just like happens
to be right every time. So, at some
point, you got to trust the guy that's
been doing this for 33 years and say
like, "All right, maybe he knows he's
talking about here. We have some other
stuff." Yeah, this is very important. We
were right. First of all, we recorded an
episode, got published yesterday. If
you're listening to this, we promise you
a follow-up. Here's the follow-up.
There's a mystery model that gave a
100red trillion tokens of availability
out to the public totally for free. They
said, "Here, come and use it. Do
whatever you want with it. It's all on
us for a full week. We're not going to
tell you who it is, though. We
discovered yesterday who it was, and it
is Z.AI. It's the people that brought
you GLM, and it's their new model, 5.3,
Flash. This looks like a normal model.
This is all fine until I was reading
through this, and I realized that all of
those tens to hundreds of trillions of
tokens that were generated were not only
generated for free, but they were
generated entirely on a chip cluster
that runs on Chinese silicon, which is a
first of its kind. I don't think we've
ever had an instance in which Chinese
silicon has produced this amount of
tokens and this amount of intelligence
>> because as the benchmarks come out we've
started to discover that it's about opus
tier agentic level which is very good
this isn't frontier but it's 15 cents
per million tokens and it understands
video audio and text so this is a really
impressive model out of China and on the
back of our robot Olympics episode ej
that we just recorded talking about how
dominant that the robots are now I'm
seeing that they are actually getting
silicon to work at scale with pretty
quick inference and a lot of it like I'm
like oh wow okay China's like they're
they're making moves this week.
>> Yeah, it's it's concerning a little bit
and I'll I'll tell you why. Recently
America or at least for the last like
four months has imposed export bans on
China, meaning that they don't allow
Nvidia to sell chips to China. Which by
the way, just to kind of reference the
quarterly earnings from Nvidia, all that
money was made by not even selling a
single chip to China. very impressive
because China was like, you know, a
major profit revenue holder. But anyway,
for the Chinese silicon, right, they're
like looking at this, they're looking at
this export band. They're like, damn, we
can't train Frontier models without
Nvidia chips. I guess we need to build
our own. And whilst they haven't built a
good enough chip that can be used to
train their own AI models, they still
use various different techniques to kind
of circumvent that, such as
distillation. they can build an amazing
chip to inference the model which by the
way is where all the money is going to
be made in AI by a vast order of
magnitude versus pre-training. So when
you look at the Chinese chip companies
about 6 months ago they were 2 and 1/2
years behind. So can someone please
explain to me how 6 months later they
are now here running the top stack of
one of the top open-source models which
happens to compete very well with US
Frontier models purely on Chinese
silicon. Now if you're wondering who's
the company that built these AI chips
look no further than Huawei. They
released a bunch of different things. I
think it's called um actually I'm I'm
not going to try and make this up cuz I
can't uh remember the name of the exact
chip but the cluster became live or got
announced about a month ago and now it's
at full scale production. Now partly
they're being forced to use these chips
because the Chinese state government has
mandated them to just not rely on Nvidia
chips for anything and they replied and
said we can't do it for training but we
can do it for inference so let us do it
and this is the first real example and I
don't know if you used uh the model when
it was in the ox alpha stage um but okay
so you you saw like it was pretty good
right like you would get a response
really quickly it was super cheap didn't
cost you anything and so it functions
very similarly to an Nvidia inference
stack and yeah it it is scary man like
What happens when they own the chip
infrastructure layer and the robotics
hardware manufacturing layer? Like what
what else is left? It's just they're
making they're making a lot of progress
in a way that's like definitely a little
unnerving. I'm like, okay, this is this
is new. And I mean this is kind of the
expectation, right? Is you like I know
Huawei is banned in the United States. A
lot of the devices you can't really get
them. They're not sold anywhere. The
inverse is happening. And what does a
country do that doesn't have access to
chips? Well, they have to go and build
their own. And now they're going to
continue to build their own and scale
them. And it's going to be really
interesting to see how this plays out.
They are not the only ones building
chips though because we have a new
company that's building chips. And this
one I'm far more excited about.
>> Something good about Google. Look at
this beauty. Is that what you're telling
me? This is Whimo.
>> Yes.
>> Whimo is looking good, man. So Whimo has
this new vehicle first of all. Ohigh.
And then even more importantly, they
have a new chip architecture that
they're introducing into this new
vehicle design. And it seems like it's a
fairly large improvement. E. And I know
you were going through the blog post, so
maybe you could walk us through. But my
understanding is that Whimo is about to
get a serious upgrade. And not in the
sense that it's going to cost less cuz
these cars, I think the number was like
$260,000 per Jaguar Whimo. Like it's
still very expensive, but the chip that
handles it is now 20 times more powerful
than it was over the last 8 years. And
that seems to make a meaningful
difference in terms of the quality of
your ride that you can actually go out
and get today. If you live in one of the
areas, you can go and ride away Moy
autonomously. I've done it. You guys, I
think you've done it. um incredible
company that has a really meaningful
upgrade to the hardware today.
>> Yeah. So, a few things with this new
chip that they just created. Um in prior
Whimo generations, so in prior vehicles,
because they have like so many sensors,
how many are there? Like 15 to 20
sensors, it's like cameras, um proximity
sensors,
>> bulky ones, man. It looks
>> I Sorry, I have to say it. I respect
Google a lot. One of the ugliest
autonomous cars out there. The new ones
are cool. The new ones are cool, but but
but mainly they've been horrific. The
point is the car has to ingest a lot of
data, translate that data into some kind
of an action, which is steer right,
steer left, break, you know, get this
person safely from A to B as quickly as
you can. Now, in order to process all
that information, you need a really
powerful AI chip. Whimo didn't have
that. So, they kind of used a hybrid of
like a chip and a cloud service. Now,
that's kind of dangerous because what if
the cloud service kind of breaks
connection? You end up being in a whole
pot of mess. Now, with this new chip, it
brings all the compute on board the
actual device. The device in this case
being a car, which I think is really
cool. So, the entire system, Josh, is
being run locally on device in the
single car. So, when in the trunk of the
car, I love that visual that they show.
>> Exactly. Yeah. Yeah. Wait, let me let me
get the the visual up. Yeah, that's why
they are showing the trunk if it wasn't
clear for the last one. It's like Yeah.
All of that compute lives sitting
underneath the trunk there.
>> So pretty cool.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And it's a single chip or or
a cluster of these different chips. And
so it takes the input data from the
sensors. It processes everything through
this one chip, which by the way is 20x
more powerful and is 5x cheaper. They
they lessen the cost. So do you remember
in our last Whimo episode, Josh, we were
like, why do each of these cars cost
like a 100k? It's because like more 260
or 200 Oh, two. Oh my god. 260k. Yes.
Now it cost 25k a car to pop out because
they were able to create the silicon
chip and reduce the cost down and run
everything.
>> This new car cost 25 grand.
>> Dude, look at this. Wait one second.
Where's the the breaking news? Yeah.
Over here. So, it used to cost 100 to
125k
Wall Street.
>> Okay. This is an important distinction.
We need to
>> talk to me. Talk to me. Tell me. Tell
me. Tell me.
>> No. No. So this is for the hardware.
This is not for the vehicle. Okay,
that's where I was getting confused. So
the hardware part is like the sensor
suite that sits on top of the vehicle.
>> So I guess it was like 125k for the last
one on top of a $100,000 vehicle. This
one's $25,000 on top of an assumed lower
cost vehicle. So okay, that's important
to say. Sorry. Sorry. Just to be clear,
this we're talking about the chip the
chip hardware here. like all of that
which kind of like, you know, makes the
car sexy and and do the cool thing,
right? And so, um, the point is with
this new chip, they've been able to
achieve a few things. Number one, it
runs locally on the car, which means
it's cheaper to run, it's way more
effective, so it's quicker, it's way
more reliable, and it's incredibly
efficient. So, it costs Google less. It
costs way more less, which is why
they've been able to kind of reduce the
cost by um like 3 to 4x, which is very
impressive for any successive
generation. I just think it's a really
cool bit of hardware device. You know,
we like hardware on this show and I'm
and I'm happy Whimo's taking this path
forward. Very cool.
>> It looks cool. It looks like a fun
science experiment. Like the car itself
looks interesting. The new Ohhigh. It's
It's fun. It's different. It looks like
Disney World. This is a really cool
promo video showing it.
>> Oh my god. Wow.
>> Yeah, it's it's like a a unique design.
I mean, granted, if you were to design a
fully autonomous car, I'm not sure why
there's two seats still facing forward
in the way they are with the steering
wheel.
>> Wait, hang on. Wait, did he turn around
in this? Let's see. Josh,
>> I'm not sure.
>> Oh, no. Oh, no. Oh, God.
>> He's turning his body around. So, we
mentioned the cost of these sensors is
it's about $25,000 for the the suite,
the hardware, the sensors. You know what
else? $25,000 each.
>> The entire cyber cab from Tesla. The
whole thing, including the vehicle, it
will be $25,000.
>> 25K per vehicle.
>> Per vehicle with the whole sensor stack.
So, what you'll notice with the Whimos
is they have this like huge amount of
spinning LAR sensors and like very
complicated sensor stack. The robo taxi
that we're seeing on screen here, the
cyber cab from Tesla has I think it's
eight cameras very similar to the ones
that are sitting in your smartphone
right now. So basically, if you imagine
the cameras on your smartphone, they are
placed into a vehicle and put in the
right place. That combined with the cost
of the actual vehicle is probably going
to fall around $25,000 in terms of cost
of goods sold. And it works and it is
being deployed starting September 3rd at
scale. So, what we see here is actual
production ready level cyber caps that
are going to be going around select few
cities in the announcement post. Could
we pull that up so I can read it off?
I'm not sure exactly which ones
>> going. I know there is one in Austin. I
know there's one in Dallas. Yeah.
Austin, Dallas, Houston, Miami, Orlando,
Tampa. If you live in any of those
places, you can go and get in a cyber
cab right now. And I think this is going
to be a really unique and interesting
inflection point for the autonomous
vehicle world in general because we have
Whimo. is making really good progress
and Whimo is right now much more
accessible. They're doing many more
miles per day and people are have gotten
comfortable with it. If you live in Los
Angeles, if you live in San Francisco,
having Whimos go around, it's just a
part of your life and you don't even
think twice about it. Now, the Cyber Cab
has an opportunity to really change that
in the sense that the cost per mile on
the Cyber Cab will be significantly less
than that of the Whimo. When you look at
the Whimo vehicle, it has like these big
bumpers that's really big and it's not a
very efficient car. The cyber cab has
much more efficiency which allows it to
decrease the cost per mile. And it's
going to be really interesting to see
how they're able to scale that because
Whimos notoriously are geofenced. They
work in very specific locations. I've
been using a Tesla fully self-driving
for years now and with no oversight.
They work anywhere. So as soon as
regulation comes online, we may see a
world in which like 12 months from now,
cyber cabs are just roaming around
everywhere and we have the opportunity
to get in them, drive them around. And
the idea is that you'll never need to
own a car because the cost per mile will
be so low that it will offset any
expenses incurred by actually buying the
physical vehicle. So really cool time
for autonomous vehicles, autonomous cars
in general. Keep an eye out for keep an
eye out for the Tesla event that's
happening next week.
>> You know where I'm not going to be
keeping my eye out in New York City
because they like to wor in New York
City, man. It sucks. It's so cool, but
it sucks like like bring us the new tech
early on for goodness sake, please. Now,
I want to have a a call out just very
quickly on this particular topic. Josh,
uh, producer Luke, we love him. He is in
one of these places. He's in Austin.
Guess how many times he's rode in a robo
taxi. Go on, guess.
>> Well, I think once, maybe.
>> I think it's zero, dude. I think it's
zero.
>> He may have done one, but it wasn't a
cyber cab.
>> I don't trust it. That image was AI
generated. I I need to see you, Luke, if
you're I know you're listening to this
cuz you're editing this right now. Like,
I need to see you in a in a cyber cab,
dude. It would be awesome. Anyway,
>> we'll check fact right here. Um, who is
our favorite investor in the world,
Josh?
>> Oh, you mean the 25-year-old who was
fired by OpenAI, raised a billion
dollars, and then had 45 and then lost
it all, and then Citadel bought it all
out, and now he's being investigated by
the SEC.
>> Wow, actually a very good succinct
summary. That's a very chat GPT, Josh.
Very impressive. Um, yes, that is
actually it.
>> Wait, but what's his name again?
>> Yeah. Leopold Ashen back.
>> Yeah, that one. That one. Yeah. Yeah,
that's right.
>> Okay, listen. Like I'm my hands are up
for those of you who are about to like
write nasty comments, right? We love
Leoport AR. I still think his thesis
isn't intact. He just, you know, don't
trade with leverage kids. But um he is
now being investigated by the SEC or
rather specifically the SEC has
subpoenaed a bunch of banks which
facilitated situational awareness funds
which is Leopold's fund trades out of
suspicion that potentially there was
inside trading. Now this is something
that we have kind of briefly referenced
and spoken about on the show. um Ajet
Balwit who is now officially Leopold
Ashener's wife is the chief of staff at
Anthropic and you know there's a few
other types of things going on there but
effectively the question is has Leopold
been kind of getting information and
trading on that information when he
should have kind of like publicly
disclosed it. We don't know but this is
just another kind of pitfall into this
whole um probe where you know Leopold's
been taking hits after hit recently. Um
he recently got back into the game
actually he's like gotten a new open
book. He made a $400 million private
investment in some other company.
Goodness knows where he got $400 million
from, but he's doing the thing. And
technically, the fund is still up. But
yeah, just curious to see where this all
ends up. I don't know if you have any
thoughts on this, Josh. Yeah, it's
mostly just like people don't like
Leopold. And what does it take to open
an investigation? You file a complaint.
Someone says, "Okay, we've acknowledged
your complaint. Now there's an open
investigation." Then you can report the
investigation. It could be nothing. It
could be something. Chances are it's
probably nothing. And I think Leopold is
just down. People want him to be down
even more and chances are he's going to
be just fine. This will kind of blow
both over and there won't really be much
that comes from it. Um, and Leopold we
trust, man. I'm still rooting for the
guy. I'm excited to see the new 13F to
see what on earth is going to be on the
comeback portfolio after the entire
public one got wiped out. So, we'll keep
our eyes peeled as we always do on
Leopold. I'm also seeing some charts
here, EJ, on Fable 5 and Anthropic and
like enterprise sales and businesses.
What is what are we showing here?
>> I I just think there's some chart
smithing going on here. So like I think
a few things going on here. So the
Financial Times released a chart and it
shows the usage of anthropics different
models over time and I don't know if you
if I can open this up Josh. I don't know
whe this makes it makes it a little
tricky for you.
>> We'll move it. We'll move it. There we
go.
>> Yeah. But if you can have a look over
here, you'll notice that Fable growth
kind of like accelerated in mid June to
the kind of the end of July and has kind
of been flat. Now, number one, I don't
know where they've got these numbers
from cuz Anthrop is not a private
company. So, I don't think these are
necessarily reliable, but the point
they're making is it has stagnated. Um,
and instead people or companies rather
are choosing to use some of their other
clawed models. Now, there are many
reasons why companies would do this,
whether it's cost, whether it's
efficiency, whether it's just kind of
like preference or taste of like the
model's personality, but it's
interesting to see that a frontier model
isn't being taken up as much as they
can. And the point that they compared
this to is that OpenAI's models have
seen increased usage. Now, my comments
on this is simple, which is OpenAI is
just like has a smaller user base than
Atropic. It's still granted very large,
but obviously any hike in usage, which
they're particularly seen with codec
specifically, which by the way is a
fantastic product is going to result in
a larger uptake or percentage increase,
right? Whereas with Fable, maybe if the
stagnation is the thing, maybe people
are just, you know, factoring in the
cost. Fable is notably, you know, more
expensive than a lot of other models,
but it is also operating at the frontier
better than any other model. So, I can
see why maybe there's a hesitancy. you
know, you've got all these new open
source models, GLM 5.3 Flash, and you're
thinking, okay, maybe if I can get 80%
of my work done using a cheap model,
I'll use Fable for the other 20%. But
the point is the pie is growing bigger
and bigger, and I think this is
>> none other than a bit of a hit piece.
>> Well, and it looks like the chart is
reflecting the pie growing bigger,
right? It's like the numbers are going
up and to the right, the the business
spending in total based on this chart
looks like it's going up. Um, and maybe
this is kind of the phenomenon that we
described earlier where there's just a
lot of demand for lowerc cost tokens,
but the overall demand is continuing to
increase. And like perhaps that is a
conclusion we can draw from this. I'm
confused what the other actually is.
Like are they talking about like haiku
or something? Because they have sonnet,
opus, fable, what else is there?
>> I'm not quite sure what's going on here.
I don't know. But hey, everyone's having
I mean the models are great on a
day-to-day basis. I'm still using it.
I'm getting a lot of usage out of it and
I'm kind of enjoying the time there. So,
it's um yeah, we'll see. I think is kind
of like where where we can leave this
one is like, okay, well, I'm I'm sorry
for enterprises, but like, hey, we're
cooking. Like, for $20 a month, $100 a
month, $200 a month, like the tokens are
flowing. I think there's a there's
another reason though, right, which is
like, did you see this whole debate
around zero days of retention? I I
started yawning when I read that phrase,
Josh, cuz I was like, "Oh my god, what
do you mean by this?" But like,
>> yeah, sounds fun. And and another big
thing for these enterprises is they want
to use the latest frontier models. And
to be honest, when you're an enterprise,
you don't care about spending more money
if it means you're going to make even
more money. So like I'll I'll spend
money on the most expensive model. But a
big compliance thing that they face is
this thing called zero data retention
where if you have a company a software
company which you kind of lease their
tools or whatever and they retain
proprietary information for their own
usage which they could technically use
to build better models which is what
anthropic has to do right now but I
believe they're in the process of
evolving that potentially who knows this
is just rumors at this point. Um I
believe you know this is something that
will just kind of flip that switch and
suddenly we'll look back on that chart
and suddenly it spiked up growth. So, I
just think this is a nothing burger. ZDR
is very common. Uh, I don't think Open
AI is enforcing it right now, which
might be the reason why they're like
accelerating faster over the last couple
of months, but just something to be
aware of. Okay, so maybe the chart is a
nothing burger, but the thing that is
real is the use of tokens. And the use
of tokens are generated mostly by
agents. And if you are working with
agents, we have just the people for you.
Their name is Ledger. Ledger is offering
a way to build with your AI agents
because if you're worried about
security, you should be because agents,
as we know, are not very secure at the
moment. They're getting very smart very
quickly. Ledger has an agent stack that
fixes this. It's a series of open source
tools that you can go and use in order
to make sure that the agent is giving
you the expected outcome that you want.
It does this through a three-step
process where the agents propose, the
humans approve, and the ledger signers
enforce. And this is all open source. It
works everywhere that you work with your
AI agents. It works in codec. It works
in cloud code. It works in cursor. So if
you are interested, the link is in the
description down below. Thank you very
much to Ledger for sponsoring this
episode. Two nothing burgers in a row.
We got to turn this around, man. Leo,
>> dude, what do we got? This is not a
nothing burger. This is a something
burger.
>> What if I gave you continual learning
robotics model? Huh?
>> Big week for the robots. First we had
the robot Olympics, then we have full
self-driving vehicles. Now we have
robotic learning. And this is one of
many announcements that I saw this week.
There was another one that I thought was
super cool where you can actually go and
get paid like $15 an hour to perform
tasks in your house. And as long as you
do that with a camera that allows you to
train the robots, you will be paid as if
you were a full-time employee. It's like
kind of cool, very fun. This is another
version of that. It seems like where
they're just basically throwing a ton of
data at these models and emerging from
that data are physical capabilities that
robots are learning from scratch. And
they're doing so in a way that's fairly
efficient. What I like about this
example that we're seeing on screen
right now too is it's not this isn't
purely humanoid. This is more of a
narrow purpose uh narrow very specific
type of robot that they're working on.
So it seems like this is a kind of new
paradigm where robots are getting enough
data to start meaningfully progress and
get good at these tasks and we're seeing
so many unique and creative ways of
collecting this data. I remember we did
one was it Door Dash or something where
they were paying dashers to strap
cameras to their heads.
>> It was Door Dash.
>> It was Door Dash. That way they can like
go and collect data for what it looks
like to deliver an item to a person's
house
>> and then taking all that data you can
>> the Pokémon Go company as well.
>> Yeah. So there's all these really
creative ways of of
>> paying humans to collect data to then
automate the tasks that they're doing.
And I think it's really cool to see the
actual progress come from this in terms
of the ability of these robots to do
more and more interesting tasks that we
as humans do and maybe we don't want to.
And I think a lot of people probably
default to like oh this is bad. We're
paying human beings to offload the
responsibilities to robots. But the
reality is is like how many people
actually love doing this stuff? Like how
many people love to clean or love to
cook or love to take the trash out or
love to like deliver food? There's
perhaps much better options on the other
side of automating that. And it results
in much lower cost for everyone who is
using those services. So this seems like
a win even though on the surface I could
see why it's scary. And this is a really
cool example of that in practice. I mean
this is a pretty sweet video.
>> Yeah. I mean, just to kind of explain
what's going on here, um, they made a
breakthrough in robotics models. Now,
typically the problem that you have with
robotics models is they're really hard
to train. In order to get the data to
teach it how to do really complex stuff,
you need to, you know, get those videos
like you mentioned, Josh, and you need
to kind of like teach it a million
different things and hardcode it into a
model. It is incredibly uh complex and
hard to do, which is why we haven't seen
a cool robot in your house as of
recently. The breakthrough these guys
made is something called in context
learning, which means you can feed this
robot one video of you making pancakes
and flipping the pancake and it'll be
able to figure it out from that
30-second video and do it itself. But
the craziest part is Josh, let's say I
filmed you making a pancake and you
flipped it and it fell on the floor,
right? The robot's seen this, right? So
presumably you would think it would do
the same.
>> Doesn't do that. It knows when you've
made a mistake and it can take it
further and start making multiple
pancakes at the same time and then
stacking them on top of each other. It
has this intuitive feel. So, an example
that they show on this video here, I
think they already passed it is it uses
uh a kind of dustban and brush to kind
of sweep a block onto the pan, right?
And then they replaced the handle with a
banana. And it was like, what would it
do in this case? It realized that it was
a banana. it realized it wasn't a brush,
but it still did the same thing and
brush the block onto the pad. So, it has
a intuitive understanding of what it
needs to do and is willing to use any
and every kind of tool to do the thing,
which is the breakthrough in this
robotics model. And I think it's going
to get us much quicker to having a robot
in our home that can intuitively just do
things without us needing to hardcode it
or tell it what to do. Very, very, so
close on the edge of the robot
>> revolution is a good way of describing
it. We had the Olympic Games that we had
a full episode about earlier this week.
So if you haven't watched that, go check
that out. Um the opening ceremony is a
little bit militant for China, which is
scary. So perhaps like you know, take
that one with a grain of salt. Um we
have a few rapid fire ones at the end of
this episode. My personal favorite here.
We have a date for the Apple event. It's
coming. It is September
>> 19.
Is this Siri AI?
>> We are finally No, it's it's not going
to happen just yet. But basically what
this one is is the hardware. There's two
types of events. There's the developer
conference, then there's the actual
hardware event. Developer conference
released or unveiled Siri. The release
of Siri will come shortly after this
hardware event. And it will come paired
with the new hardware devices. The new
hardware devices are expected to be a
new iPhone 18 Pro, a foldable device,
which I'm incredibly excited to get my
hands on. And more importantly, this is
the first event with Apple's new CEO in
charge. Tim Cook isn't going to be on
stage here. It's uh John Turnis, who's
running it. There's a new guy in charge.
He's a hardware guy. This is all the new
hardware we're going to be getting
specifically built for Apple
intelligence. And man, we've been
waiting for this for what, three years
to get actual intelligence inside these
phones. So, very excited to see how
that's going to play out, what the
hardware is going to look like, how the
software will integrate with it.
>> And probably a month from now, we will
all have brand new iPhones with Siri
intelligence inside of them. And that is
a very exciting thing. So,
>> fingers crossed.
>> The the chip thing is cool, right? I saw
the M5 Pro and the M6 kind of get
announced and the price of those are
>> new Mac Mini, new Mac Studio
>> kind of up there, right? So, it's like I
think it's like 900 bucks for the M6 or
And then he 500 for the M5.
>> Have you heard the high end of the
studio?
>> Go on. The
>> Wait, let me guess. Let me guess. Let me
guess. You're going to be wrong.
>> $3,000. No,
>> I think it's like $18,500
>> for the if you want a maxed out Mac
Studio with like the M6 Ultra and all
the RAM that you can get. It's crazy how
expensive these things have gotten. But
hey, if you got the money and you want
to run some local inference, there's
your cost of entry. All these people
talking about free model. Buy an Nvidia
GPU at this point, dude. Like, what what
are we doing here? Free model, free
model that. Like, just how about you
just pay for like a subscription or like
an API key and like let the big guys
serve your inference because it's
getting real expensive to do it locally.
>> By the way, blame the memory
manufacturers for this. That's why the
price is hiking across everything right
now.
>> Everything.
>> And they got great margins, too. I was
looking at video earnings. I'm like,
man, these people are charging way too
much money for this. They're driving up
all the prices.
>> Last topic. I thought this was really
funny, EJ, as you put it in. It's like,
I'm a watch guy. Yeah. So, basically,
breaking news, guys. Arguably the
biggest topic of this entire episode.
Sam Alman just ordered seven ultra rare
custom Swiss watches from this company
called Van. I'm definitely butchering
that name. With a branded open air logo
on the D. No commentary, right? First,
let's observe. Look at this masterpiece.
For those who like wear Apple watches, I
need you to just take that thing off
your wrist for a second and just
appreciate the mastery that is on your
screen right now.
>> This looks so Can we Can we take a
second? Cuz I just so happen to have an
Apple Watch in my hand.
>> Um it appears like the band on my Apple
Watch looks oddly similar to the band on
that watch.
>> Absolutely. Um, and that is because the
memory component, the equivalent of this
is that complex cognitive function that
is happening inside the thing. Who cares
about the plastic strap? You can
literally, you see this little
attachment over here?
>> How many per second does that generate?
>> Oh god, not enough. Not enough. But um,
inscribed on the back of each of these
watches is if AGI.aligned
deploy was written by a programming
language python.vanguard.
So the point is I think this is like you
know Sam kind of like giving a peace
offering before a potential rumored IPO
that I think is coming very soon and he
wants to give it to his ranking order of
people that haven't left open air over
the last two weeks. Sorry for the sorry
for the shade. I've just seen a lot of
executives leave recently. But it's a
beautiful watch. Um people have been
discussing what the secondary value of
this might be. Um and people are
guesstimating this would be in the order
of 500k to a million dollars. I
personally think it would be higher
because there's only seven of them. Um
and one of them will be worn by Sam's on
Sam's wrist. So that's definitely not
getting this is kind of like um what it
like the push presents like when when
your like wife has a child. It's like
when your executives produce AGI saying
please please turn off now. Thank you.
>> Well this like I think this makes sense,
right? It's like when your executives
produce AGI like hey guys thanks like
here's a million dollar watch type
thing. Um because I was listening to Sam
Alman or I was reading the time
publication of Sam Alman and what he was
saying and they fully expect to have AGI
internally by the end of this year and
for those that are not familiar we are
about to enter September which means we
are close to the end of this year. So
maybe perhaps he's getting these custom
made in anticipation of their internal
rollout of AGI whatever they believe
that to be. Um so that's just an
interesting thing worth noting worth
following. Lovely watches like hey the
Limitless guys I I mean I'd take a half
million dollar watch
a million whatever it's going to cost
that'd be cool. That's the round it.
This is a long one today. We're like 40
minutes into this thing. Um, so if you
made it this far, man, thanks for coming
along with us on this journey. It's been
a good one. A lot of stuff happening
this week. The the thing things are
picking themselves up. The roundup's
getting longer. There's more stuff to
talk about. I say this is a big robotics
week this week. A lot of robots, a lot
of China talk this week. Good week for
the Chinese.
>> Whether it's for us, we don't know TBD,
but like good week for the Chinese, good
week for Nvidia.
>> It's good for Limalis as well, though.
We're putting out so much content, so
much to talk about. Um, what was the
other thing that was like the open rail
acquisition that might have been last
week's news? Who knows?
>> Track, man.
>> We are covering anything and everything
that is happening in AI and Frontier
Tech or whatever just makes, you know,
Josh and I pretty excited. And we're
doing that four times a week. So, if you
haven't listened to any of our other
episodes this week, please check it out.
We also have a newsletter that goes out
to, I think it's like 110,000 of you
that are reading our stuff every single
week. Twice a week we do an essay and we
also do the weekly roundup which if you
don't want to listen to our beautiful
soothing voices telling you about AI,
you can just go read the quick summary
digest. We are covering you everywhere
on Spotify, Apple as well as YouTube. If
you aren't subscribed, if you haven't
left us a comment, if you haven't given
us a rating, what are you doing? Please
do all of that. Send it, share it with a
friend. It helps us out massively. Josh,
have I forgotten anything? I mean, you
can, and I know this is kind of rough
for me to say because I haven't been
posting much, but on screen are our our
handles on X are showing, and you can go
and follow us there for more information
on the day-to-day. I know you're always
reading off stuff about updates. That's
just like a fun little call out if you
made it this far. Um, and you know,
you're interested in hearing a little
bit more. I'll work to post more on that
platform, but that's it. Like you're you
can go feel free to like you're
dismissed. Go touch grass, go enjoy the
weekend, get off your phone for a little
bit. You're now fully up to date and all
the things AI Frontier technology.
You're in the loop. You can go out to
your like weekend barbecue. I mean,
close to the end of the weekend. We're
almost We're almost there. I don't want
to think about that. But yeah, that's
pretty much everything. Thank you so
much. I mean, share with your friends if
you if you got some that would be
interested. And yeah, enjoy the weekend.
We'll see you guys next week.